자.. 분석 해볼까
Let's break it down.
수소,
우리가 얻은 수소의 양이 얼마지?
Hydrogen.
What does that give us?
흡수된 것 까지?
63%로 나왔어
By mole?
We're looking at 63%.
63?
오.. 많네
That is a big bite.
다음으로, 산소를 볼까?
My next step's
gotta be oxygen.
산소: 26%
Oxygen: 26%.
26%,
그럼, 89%의 H20가 생성되는군
26.
There you have your water.
탄소: 9%
Carbon: 9%.
탄소, 9%
Carbon: 9.
- 그럼 총합이 98%?
- 응
- For a total of 98%?
- Right.
- 질소: 1.25%
- 1.25
- Nitrogen: 1.25%.
- 1.25.
응.. 그걸로 99.25%가 된거지
That brings it
to 99 and a quarter.
마술같은 이 화학반응이 남긴,
Which only leaves you
with the trace elements
나머지 요소는 뭐가있지?
down where the magic happens.
잠깐, 칼슘은 어떻게 되지?
Oh, wait a minute.
What about calcium?
칼슘의 흔적은 없어?
Calcium's not a trace.
사람 몸에 뼈가 얼마나 많은데
Got a whole skeleton
to account for.
- You would think, right?
- Right.
칼슘은 0.25% 뿐이야
Calcium. Calcium is only .25%.
뭐?
그렇게 적어?
What?
That low?
진짜야?
Seriously?
그럼, 어떻게 된거야?
Damn, I never would
have thought that.
철은 어디에 가 붙은거지?
Okay, so where
does iron fit in?
철... 아, 그래
Iron. Wow, okay.
0.00004%
.00004%.
뭐?
What?
철 없는 헤모글로빈이 있을 순 없잖아
You can't have hemoglobin
without iron.
- 물론이지
- 그렇지.. 자.. 또 보자
- Apparently, it don't take much.
- No, it don't. Go figure.
- 소듐은?
- 소듐: 0.04%
- Sodium.
- Sodium:.04.
인(燐): 0.19%
Phosphorus:.19.
0.19%
자, 그럼..
.19.
There we go.
전체를 모두
So, the whole thing...
합하면,
adds up to...
99.888042%.
그럼, "0.111958%" 가 남네
We are .111958%...
아주 작은 양이긴 하지만..
shy.
이게, 우리가 분석 해 낸 전부야
Supposedly
that's everything.
아.. 진짜 모르겠네
I don't know.
I just... I just...
뭘, 빼 먹은 것 같긴 한데..
그게 뭐지?
Just seems like
something's missing, doesn't it?
우리가 분석 해내지 못 한,
"0.111958%" 는 대체 뭐지?
There got to be more
to a human being than that.
Breaking Bad
Season 01 Χ Epsiode 03
Synchro : Tyno
Transcript : SwSub
배포는 마음껏 !
수정은 절대금지
FeedBack, 적극 환영
이번 3화부턴, HDTV로 제작되어
화질이 엄청 좋아짐
www.forom.com
www.sub-way.fr
제작: [ 시 건 방 ]
dynas3@daum.net
college of Law in Korea Univ. 1.
이 신발이 싫어
I hate these shoes.
이 신발을 신으면,
마치, 변기에 앉아..
These shoes make me look like
I should be changing bedpans,
스프 끓여 달라며,
like I should be squeaking
around bringing soup
짜증나게 구는..
to some disgusting old person,
노인네처럼 보인다니까
then take the bus home
to my 16 cats.
근데, 왜 그걸 신고 다녀요?
Then why are you
wearing them?
이게 편하니까
I like the support.
편한것 만큼, 좋은게 없어
My arches happen to be
extremely archy.
어.. 왜?
Yo. What's up?
2분후에 다시 전화 할래?
Hey, can you call me,
like, in two minutes?
고마워
Thanks. Bye.
잠깐 나갔다 올께요
Gotta go take this.
여자니?
Female?
루이스
Louis.
엄마가 상관할 건, 아니지 않어?
Not like it's any
of your business, though.
빨리 들어와라
Just be quick about it.
그런식으로 말하지마
Oh, and, um,
please don't say yo.
그런식으로 말하는 거..
내가 얼마나 싫어하는지 모르지?
You can't know
how much I hate that.
저 쪽, 빼 먹었다
You missed a... spot right there.
사다리 위에 올가가도 괜찮냐, 너?
Should you be
up on that ladder?
언니가 직접 하는게,
더 나을 것 같은데..
You're more than welcome
to take over for me up here.
월터를 왜 그냥,
놔 두고 있는거야?
I don't see why you don't
just get Walt to do it.
나도, 생각이 있어
Yeah.
There's an idea.
그냥 단순하게,
그냥..
So, I'm working
on this new short story,
그이가 다 알아서 하게끔..
and there's this stoner character in it,
and I'm trying to...
예전으로 다시 돌아갈 수
있게끔 하고 싶을뿐야
Well, know you,
actually, let me back up.
언니, 대학다닐 때..
You've smoked your
녹찻잎 좀 했었지?
(*녹찻잎 : 대마초의 은어)
fair share of pot
in college, didn't you?
좀 했었잖아..
I mean, you at least tried it.
괜찮아
Come on.
그래, 년아..
좀 했다, 왜?
I perhaps tried it. Why?
그거 하면, 어떤 느낌인데?
Do you rember it having
an effect on your mood,
기분이 바뀐다든지..
뭐.. 그런거
like changing it
in any major way, or...
난, 더 기분이 안 좋아지더라
It made me more serious.
왜?
Really?
흔히 알기론
Because I mostly rember
머리도 가벼워지고,
기분 좋아진다지 않아?
it made me light-headed.
That's about it.
내 소설에,
대마초 하는
I was just wondering
if it maybe could...
캐릭터를 등장 시키면,
어떨까 해서
You know, it's just
a character thing I'm stuck on.
뭐, 암튼..
Never mind.
- 니 아들, 대마초 하는구나?
- 뭐?
- Walter Jr.'s on pot?
- What?
아냐, 아냐
No! No.
- 왜 그래.. 언니?
- 걔, 그거 어디서 났대?
- What would make you even...
- Where's he getting it from?
- 언니..?
- 아까 전화 온 루이스라는 놈 한테서?
- Marie.
- Seriously. Is it this Louis person?
너, 알면서도 뭐하고 있는거니?
What are you going
to do about this?
언니, 진정 좀 해
You need
to look me in the eye.
내가 쓰고 있는 소설, 캐릭터 땜에
물어본거야.. 그게 전부야
I am strictly asking about a story
that I am writing, that's all.
맹세컨데, 내 아들은
절대 녹찻잎 안 씹어!
Right hand to God,
Walter Jr. is not on pot.
내가 아는 한, 확실해
Certainly not
as far as I know.
니가 아는 한?
Not as far as you know?
언니...
Marie.
Breaking Bad
뷁king Bad
뷁킹 Bad
뷁킹 배d
뷁킹 배드
Brea킹 배드
Breaking 배드
Breaking Ba드
Breaking Bad
좀, 보쇼
Look at me.
얘기 좀.. 합시다
Hey, turn around
and look at me.
이거.. 이거 좀
This...
This here...
아무리 적이라도 그렇지..
이렇게 까진 안한다구
I wouldn't do this
to my worst enemy.
너무 심한거 아니오?
This is degrading.
미안하네
I'm sorry.
일 처리 하기 쉽게,
내가 그냥 죽어주길 바라는 거요?
You hope I'll make it easy on you
and just drop dead, don't you?
그리, 쉽게 되진 않을꺼요
Well, I won't.
날 풀어주든지, 죽이든지..
So either kill me
or let me go.
안그래요, 월터?
You don't have it
in you, Walter.
내 이름을 어떻게 알았나?
How do you know my name?
저 새끼..
Jesse.
저새끼한테 들었소
He told Emilio and me.
아저씨가 만든 거, 팔러 왔을 때
When he came by
to sell your meth?
저녀석을 위협해서 알아낸건가?
So what?
You threaten him, huh?
- 저녀석을 팼나?
- 아니오
- Did you beat it out of him?
- Not even close.
저녀석이 또, 뭐 뭐 말하던가?
What else did he tell you?
아저씨에 대해
꽤 많은 걸 얘기했소
Pretty much everything
you can think of.
아저씨..
고삐리들 선생이라면서요?
How you were his
high school teacher.
수업시간에.. 탄소화합물로,
포도소다 만드는 것도 갈켜줬다고..
How one time you taught about carbon
dioxide by making grape soda in class.
휠체어나 목발에 의지 해야만 하는
How you have a son
who's retarded,
지체마비 장애 아들이 있다는 것도 들었소
or in a wheelchair
or something.
하루이틀 일이 아니고..
This shouldn't come across
as some news flash.
저새낀, 원래..
That partner of yours...
입이 존나 싸요
he's got a big mouth.
왜 아저씨가,
여기서 이러는지 몰겠어요
Walter, I don't know what you
think you're doing here,
아저씨랑 안 어울리게,
왜 이 짓을 하는 거죠?
but trust me, this line of work
doesn't suit you.
내가 자넬 풀어주면,
So I should just
let you go, then?
자넨, 날 여기에 가두고 튀겠지?
Just unlock you
and adios, huh?
난, 아저씨가..
사람을 죽일만큼
I don't see what
real choice you have
냉혈한은 아닐꺼라고 봐요
if it's between that
and cold-blooded murder.
게다가..
Besides...
아저씨의 진짜 문제는
윗층에 있지 않나요?
your real problem
is sitting upstairs.
똥 눠여
Occupied!
똥 싸고 있다고요 ~
Hey, yo, I'm trying
to pinch one off in here!
똥 싸는건 좀 놔둬요..
간섭하지말고
Just give me
some privacy, would ya?
왜 그래요, 진짜?
What the hell, man?
모하는 거예요?
What are you doing, man?
- 아, 씹라
- 내 이름을 말했지?
- You asshole!
- You told him my name.
- 누구한테요?
- 내 이름.. 내 직장
- Says who? Him?
- My name, where I work.
- 그리고 내 아들까지?
- 놔요, 좀..
- You told him about my son!
- Don't touch me!
- 이따위, 쓰레기
- 안돼요, 안돼
- Damn junkie!
- No, give me that!
변기에나 쳐 넣어 버리겠어
Too late! This is going down
the toilet. Watch it go!
40그랜트 짜리예요,
미쳤어요?
No, that's worth 40 grand,
you stupid shit.
니가 피우면, 아무 가치도 없다
It's worth nothing
when you smoke it all.
비켜, 변기에서
Get off the toilet.
비키라고
Get off the toilet!
나와!
안돼!
Stop it!
절대 못 나간다!
No! No way!
뭐하자는 거예요, 지금?
What the hell do you
think you're going?
- 놔요, 좀!
- 해야 할 일이 많다
- Back off, man! Jesus!
- We've got work to do!
아뇨,
내 몫은 다 했어요
No, you got work to do.
I did my part.
내가 두시간을 청소하는 동안,
넌 약이나 쳐 빨고 있었잖아?
You mean that obscenity that I spent
the last two hours cleaning up?
- 그게 도와주는거냐?
- 좃이나 까 쳐 드세요
- That is your contribution?
- Yo! Kiss my pink ass, man!
내 집이 이렇게 망가졌어요
I didn't ask
for any of this!
난 이제 여기서 어떻게 살아요? 씨발
How am I supposed
to live here now, huh?
집 전체가 시체 썪는 냄새와
세제 냄새로 진동을 하잖아요
My whole house smells like
toe cheese and dry cleaning.
내가 하라는 대로..
안해서 그런거잖아
Because you didn't
follow my instructions!
오 ~ 그러세요?
하일, 히틀러! .... 씨발
Oh, well,
heil Hitler, bitch.
더 말해 볼까요?
And let me tell you
something else.
동전 던지기로 결정했잖아요
We flipped a coin,
okay?
선생님하고 나하고
You and me.
둘이서
You and me!
동전던지기로 결정난거잖아요
Coin flip is sacred.
Damn it.
선생님 할 일은, 지하실에 있어요
Your job is waiting for you
in that basement,
동전던지기 했으니까
as per the coin.
그거나 하시라구요.. 씨발
Fucking do it already.
걔가 그랬어
That's what she said.
응, 우리가 좀 있으니까
니가 하라구
Yeah, I think we have some of those.
Yeah, you'll have to try them on.
아가씨?
- Hello.
- 7? maybe. I don't know.
아가씨?
이거 까만색으로 있어요?
Excuse me.
Do you have these in black?
Anyway, so like I was saying,
I went to the party the other night.
Yeah, Tony was there.
여보, 어딨었어?
두시간 전부터 전화 했는데
Hey, where have you been?
I called you two hours ago.
미안, 좀 바빠서.. 왜?
Sorry, baby. I'm kinda
busy here. What's up?
응, 좀.. 민감한 문젠데
Kind of a lot, actually,
and it's a delicate subject,
당신한테 할 얘기가 좀 있어
so I need you to focus and...
앉아!
앉아, 이 새꺄!
Hey, sit down!
Sit down!
뭐야, 여보?
Damn it, Hank.
미안, 미안
지금..
Well, sorry, babe.
I'm just...
일 하는 중이야
I'm kind of in the middle
of something here.
앉아, 이새꺄!
Sit down!
Sit your ass down!
너도 쳐 앉으라고, 이 개새꺄
Comprende?
You, too! Sit down!
죽을래, 이 씹새꺄?
Si?tete!
어.. 여보,
왜?
I'm back, baby.
What's up?
월터 주니어
Walter Jr.
응, 걔가 왜?
Yeah,
what about him?
대마초
Marijuana.
걔가 그걸 하는 거 같애
- He's smoking it.
- Bullshit.
스카일러가 그렇게 생각하는거 같애
Excuse me.
His own mother seems to think so.
- 처제가 그래?
- 아니, 짐작이..
- Skyler told you that?
- She inferred it.
그니까, 짐작일 뿐이잖아
She inferred it, huh?
근데, 내 추측이 맞는거 같애
She strongly
inferred it, like...
이녀석이 아무래도 장애가
있으니까 그것 땜에..
"Doctor, my friend suffers
from erectile dysfunction."
일찍 들어와, 여보
얘기 좀 해
Please, come on already.
I want you to talk to him.
걔네 엄마, 아빠가 직접
혼 내 주는게 낫지 않어?
Walt should. Skyler, better yet. She'll
kick his butt up and down the block.
당신이 좀..
알아듣게 혼 좀 내줘
I think
it ought to be you.
그러면 안된다고,
좀 알아듣게 타일러봐
You know, tell him
some horror stories.
무서운 사진같은 것도
보여줘가면서..
Maybe show him
some autopsy pictures.
대마초 과다흡입해서 죽은
시체 부검 사진같은거 말야?
What, autopsy for
a pot overdose? Come on.
글쎄.. 그건 말야
I don't know, baby.
It's just that, you know...
지 아빠가 직접
혼내줘야 될 일 아닌가?
I figure his dad should be the one
doing this thing, don't you think?
여보, 걔는
당신말 잘 듣잖아
Hank, he respects you.
그래, 알았어
일 끝나고 가볼께
Yeah, all right. Well, listen,
I'll swing by their place after work.
정신이 바짝들게,
따끔하게 혼 좀 내 줘
Good. Scare him straight.
자기 목소리, 오늘 섹시한데?
Where's my sugar?
손님?
죄송한데요..
Excuse me, ma'am.
Ma'am.
양말 착용하고 신어봐야 하거든요?
You need to be wearing footies
before you try those on.
아주 아주 깨끗해요
I'm extremely clean.
예, 그러시겠죠
Yeah, well,
I'd really appreciate it.
Hey, sorry about that.
Yeah, I'll check.
You know, I hid a pair
for you last week, gray ones,
but my manager found them, and
we had to put them back on the floor.
어떻게 생각해?
What do you think?
뭘요?
About what?
여기, 이 광경 말야
This look
like a nice place?
안 좋은데요
No, not really.
이 딴데 살고 싶냐?
Think you'd like
to live here?
아녀
No.
- 정말, 그렇게 생각해?
- 당삼이져, 삼촌
- You sure about that?
- Yeah, pretty sure.
우리.. 우유 사러 가는 길 아녔어요?
I thought we were going
to Cold Stone Creamery.
응, 그냥 이쪽으로 돌아가는거야
Well, a little detour.
이런 동네에 사는 사람들도
봐 보라고.. 어떻게들 사는가
Figured we'd come over here
and check out how the other half lives.
이 동네를 크리스탈이라고 불러
This here's what we call
the Crystal Palace.
여긴, 어떤 사람들이 사는지 아냐?
Now you know who lives in the palace?
Meth-heads.
드럽고, 메스껍고, 뭐 그런
마약중독자들이나 사는 동네야
Nasty, skeevy,
meth-heads
지들 할머니랑도 하는,
그런 새끼들이야
who'd sell their grandma's
coochie for a hit.
웃기지?
이 동네, 아주 깬다니까
Oh, you think that's funny?
That's funny, huh? Yeah.
얘네들이, 어찌해서..
Well, let me tell you something.
Every last one of these
이 따위로 살게 됐는지 아냐?
miserable wastes of skin
got started how?
- 얘네들이 뭘로 시작했을 것 같애?
- 몰라요
- How do you think they got started?
- I don't know.
얘네들을 마약 중독에까지 이르게 한,
What do you think it was they were
all doing before they graduated
일명, 초보자用 마약이 있어
to shooting meth in their...?
게이트웨이 드럭
A gateway drug.
그렇게 불러
That's what we call it.
마약에 입문하게 되는, 첫 게이트웨이
Dollars to doughnuts,
and I shit you not,
그 초보자用 마약이..
바로, "대마초"야
that gateway drug
was marijuana.
Every time.
- 알겠어?
- 예
- You understand?
- Um, yeah.
근데, 왜 나한테..
이런 얘기를..?
So why are you
telling me this?
널 사랑하니까 그러지.. 이 자식아
'Cause I love you,
you little bastard.
내가 어렸을 때,
Hey, I was young once,
you know?
세상이 아주 혼란했던 적이 있었어
The world's a messed up place,
you know?
그 땐,
You know,
there was this...
그땐 어땠냐면...
this one time when...
Hey!
어이, 이거 봐
Hey! Hey, you!
아가씨!
Yeah, you, princess!
아가씨, 잠깐만!
Get over here!
날, 차에서 내리게 할건가?
Don't make me
get out of the car!
잘 봐라
Check this out.
잘 들어봐라
See what I'm talking about.
- 난, 아무 짓 안했거든?
- 입 벌려봐
- I ain't holdin', okay?
- Did I say you could open your mouth?
차에서 손 떼고!
And hands of the car.
이 쪽으로 돌아가 봐
Other side.
Go around the other side.
여기, 이 친구한테 말야
Talk to my friend here.
아가씨, 이름 뭐야?
What's your name,
sweetheart?
- 웬디
- 웬디?
- Wendy.
- Wendy, huh?
아가씨, 얼마면 돼?
How much you charge
for a windy, Wendy?
- 얘랑?.. 얜, 애기잖아
- 누가 그거 하래?
- I ain't doing him. He's a kid.
- Jesus, was that my question?
돌대가리 같은 년아
Don't think so hard.
It's gonna hurt your brain.
녹차 빨았지?
아님, 히로뽕 꽂았어?
Are you on the pipe
or the needle?
아냐, 암것도 안했어
Nothing. Neither.
이 ~.. 해봐
Show us your teeth, huh?
진주같이 하얀 이빨 좀 보여줘 봐
Come on, Wendy,
let's see those pearly whites.
봤어?
Oh, God. See that?
하, 그년.. 담배 무쟈게 펴 댔구만
Pipe. Definitely.
오래 됐구만.. 담배 핀 지.
Big time. Big time
on the pipe.
- 웬디에게 뭐 궁금한 거 있어?
- 아뇨, 아뇨
- You got something you wanna ask Wendy?
- No, not really.
웬디, 입에 무는 거..
그거 말고 또 뭐있지?
You ever smoke
anything else, Wendy?
쏘세지.. ㅋ
Sausages don't count.
그건 됐고
Seriously.
담배 핀 지 얼마나 됐는지,
이 친구에게 말해줘 봐
Tell my friend here
how you got started.
아마.. 걸 스카웃 때 쯤
부터 했지 싶네, 안그래?
You probably used to be,
what, like, a Girl Scout
- 아님, 교회 성가대 때 부터?
- 얜, 어디 장애 있나 봐?
- or probably sang in a church choir?
- What are you, like, handicapped?
축구하다 다리 좀 다쳤어
He broke his leg
playing football.
포지션이 쿼터백이야
He's a QB.
곡사포같은 엄청난 팔을 가졌다구
Got an arm
like a howitzer.
웬디, 대마초 빨았지?
So tell me, Wendy,
do you smoke pot?
- 있음, 좀.. 줄래?
- 됐어,.. 꺼젼 년아
- Why, you got some?
- All right. Hoof it. Get lost.
꺼져..
담에 보면, 확 그냥..
Get out of here. Hey, fair warning!
Next time I'm gonna bust you!
그래, 소감이 어떠니?
So what do you think?
쿨한데요?
Cool.
by. 시 건 방
dynas3@hanmail.net
문 닫어,
문닫어..
Shut the door.
문 걸어,
문걸어..
Lock it.
저것들은 뭐야?
Who the hell was that?
짭새 한마리랑,
축구선수래나 뭐래나..
A cop and some football player
messing with me.
나에 대해, 뭐 묻더나?
They ask about me? Huh?
아니.. 녹차 사려고 온 것 같애
No. I think
they just wanted pot.
뭐야.. 싼거야, 벌써?
Oh, shit.
I left my root beer.
[죽이지 말아야 할 이유]
LET HIM LIVE
도덕적, 윤리적으로 당연한 것
IT'S THE MORAL THING TO DO
당당하게 살 수 없기 때문
WON'T BE ABLE TO LIVE WITH YOURSELF
살인은 죄!
MURDER IS WRONG!
[죽여야 하는 이유]
내 가족 모두에게 복수해 올 것임
KILL HIM, HE'LL KILL YOU ENTIRE
FAMILY IF YOU LET HIM GO
여보세요
Hello.
여보, 나야
Hey, sweetie,
it's me.
미안하게 됐어
Listen, I'm so sorry.
지금 여기 너무 바빠서..
The time, it just completely
got away from me there.
미안해, 미안해
사장이 늦게 까지 잡아두네..
My fault. My fault.
Bogdan just kept me here late,
재고 정리를 좀 해야된대..
you know, doing
some inventory, and...
뭐, 어쩔수 없는거잖아..
I've... I should have just...
당신 말이 맞아.. NO! 라고
말하는 법을 배워햐 해, 난.
You know, you're right.
I gotta learn to say, you know, no!
근데, 오늘은...
But, um...
여보, 듣고있어?
Sky? You there?
당신..
세차장 이라구요?
You're at the car wash?
응
Yeah.
아닌 것 같은데?
I seriously doubt that,
2주 전에 그만 뒀 잖아요
since you quit two weeks ago.
세차장에 전화 해 봤더니
I called Bogdan,
looking for you.
그리 말하더군요
Quite an earful
he gave me.
내 말 들어봐, 여보
Listen...
집에 가서, 말 해 줄께
Listen, I'll come home,
and we'll talk about it.
듣고 싶지 않아요, 월트
I don't think so, Walt.
여보?
Honey.
어디냐가 문제가 아니라,
Wherever you are...
왜, 오늘 못 들어 온다는거죠?
why don't you just
stay there tonight?
스카일러?
Skyler?
여보?
아저씨
Walter!
배 고파요
Kind of hungry
down here!
Damn.
못 깨어 날 줄 알았어요
I didn't think
you were coming back.
얼마나 오래 됐나?
How long was I out?
10.. 15분 정도
10, 15 minutes.
기침하다가 넘어지는 사람은 첨 봐요
I've never seen someone knock
themselves out just by coughing.
평소처럼 숨을 쉰 건가요?
You breathe in the same
thing you used on me?
난.. 폐암일쎄
I've got lung cancer.
다시 갖다 주겠네
I'll go make you
another sandwich.
괜찮어
It's safe.
독 안 들었어
There's no poison.
Yeah?
날 죽일 맘이 있다면
Because that'd be
the way to do it...
얼마든지,
그런 식으로 할 수 있잖아요
if you're gonna do it.
그렇겠지
I suppose it would.
아저씬, 화학 선생이잖아요
I mean, you being
a chemist and all.
그래...
So...
자네 이름...
that name...
크레이지-8...
Krazy-8...
정말, 그렇게 불러도 되나?
Do I really have
to call you that?
내 말은,
I mean, no offense, but...
자네 진짜 이름은 뭐냔거지
don't you have
a real name?
도밍고
Domingo.
일요일이란 뜻이네?
That's "Sunday," right?
괜찮다면, 난 도밍고라고 부르겠네
I'd rather call you that,
if you don't mind.
좋으실 대로요
Yeah, whatever.
내가 뭐,
지금 그걸 가릴 입장도 아니고.
I can't say
I ever liked it much.
그래, 도밍고..
So, Domingo...
여기가 고향인가,
아님, 딴데서 이사 온 건가?
are you from around town
here or someplace else?
날 알아 갈 수록..
Walter,
you getting to know me
날 죽이기만 힘들거요
is not gonna make it
easier for you to kill me.
안 그래요?
Not that I mind,
you understand.
계속 말하게
You know,
you keep telling me
난 그럴 맘 없으니
that I don't have it in me.
Well, maybe.
아마도 그래.
But maybe not.
자넬 죽일 이유가 없네
I sure as hell am looking
for any reason not to.
전혀 없어
I mean,
any good reason at all.
괜찮아
Sell me.
뭐라도 말해보게
Tell me what it is.
날 풀어줄 경우,
당신에게 복수 하지 않을꺼라고
I guess I'd start off
by promising that,
약속한다면,
if you let me go,
I won't come after you.
그냥 조용히 갈 것이라고
약속한다면,
That you'd be safe.
여기서 뭔 일이 있었는지
I guess I'd say what happened
between us...
말하지 않겠다고 약속한다면,
never happened.
아저씨는,
내 말을 믿을 껀가요?
And what's best for both parties
is we forget all about it.
누구든, 나같은 상황에선..
일단 그런 약속을 하고 보겠죠
But you know that anybody in my
situation would make promises like that.
내가 진짜로 그 약속을
지킬 맘이 있다해도
And though in my case
they happen to be true,
아저씨 입장에서,
내 말을 믿을 수 있을까요?
you'd never know
for sure.
내가 무슨 말을 더 해야 할까요?
So what else
can I tell you?
나도 모르겠네
I don't know.
하지만, 난 자넬 믿네
But you gotta convince me.
자네가 약속하기 전까진,
풀어줄 수 없네
And you're going nowhere
until you do.
Hey, yeah. Yeah.
난 어릴때 부터 이 동네서 살았어요
I'm from here
in town, man.
이 동네에서 태어나고 자랐어요
ABQ. Born and bred.
이 동넬 떠난 적이 없어요
Never left.
뉴멕시코 대학에서,
Studied business
administration over at UNM,
경제학을 전공했어요
got my degree.
그래?
Really?
그 좋은 지식을 마약시장에 써 먹다니..
Does that come in handy
in the drug trade?
맘이 아프군
It doesn't hurt.
전 원래, 음악을 공부하고 싶었어요
I was gonna study
music originally.
버클리나 오벌린음대에 가려했죠
Maybe even try out
for Oberlin or Berklee.
근데.. 그런 음악으론
먹고살긴 힘들잖아요
My pops talked me
out of it.
락스타 따위가 되지 않는 한,
돈도 벌 수 없고
Said there was no money in it unless
I wind up some bullshit rock star,
결국, 내가 음악 할 기회는
잡질 못했어요
and I didn't have
a snowball chance of that, man.
자네 아버지는 뭐 하시나?
What does your dad do?
메뉼에서 탐피코 가구점을 하세요
He owns Tampico Furniture
over on Menaul.
잠깐..
들어 본 것 같은데
Wait a minute.
I know that place.
잠깐만
Wait a minute.
That's...
그게... 뭐드라..
That's that...
주로, 밤 늦게
They used to have
those late-night...
- 이상한 CM송으로 광고 때렸잖아
- 예, 맞아요
Those stupid commercials.
Yeah, that's him.
- 그 CM을 30년 넘게 썼어요
- 잠깐만..
- He's been doing 'em for over 30 years.
- Wait a minute.
어떻게 시작 하더라...
How did it go?
It was, uh...
잠깐, 잠깐..
어..
Wait, wait, wait.
It was...
Don't let shopping
Strain your brain-o
Just sing this short refrain-o
Our forniture is bueno
Tampico is the name-o.
참.. 깨는 거였죠
Pretty moronic.
하지만, 아저씨도 그걸 따라하잖아요
But what can you do?
단순해서,
은근히 중독성 있더라구
It did tend
to stick in your head.
그 CM은 자네가 만든건가?
Did you write that,
being the musician of the family?
아뇨
Hell, no, man.
알렉스라고.. 우리 날라리 삼촌이요
It was my crazy Uncle Alex.
술집같은데서..
여자 꼬실때 부르고 그랬어요
He sings it at bars,
trying to pick up on women.
삼촌 딴엔, 그래도..
In his mind,
it's like saying,
"Stairway to Heaven" 이랑 동급이래나? ㅋ
(*레드제플린의 노래)
"I wrote Stairway to Heaven."
잠깐만,
탐피코 퍼니쳐라...
Wait a minute.
Tampico Furniture.
그래 맞다.. 우리 아들 태어났을 때
거기서 등나무요람을 샀었어
I think when my son was born
that we bought his bassinet there.
요람을 팔진 않았는데..
그건, 좀 더 전문적 아이템이예요
We don't sell bassinets there.
It's more of a specialty item.
애기침대를 만들어 팔았죠
We did use
to sell cribs.
아, 그래.. 애기침대였다
Oh. Well, a crib, then,
okay? Crib.
아.. 그래 이제 기억난다
Yeah. No, I remember that.
사실은,
In fact,
자네 아버지를 기억할것 같네
I remember recognizing your dad
from those commercials.
자네 아버진..
Although he wasn't...
친구가 별로 없더군
anywhere near as friendly
in real life.
예..
Yeah, no shit.
보증기간 늘려 준다는 말에
혹해서 뭐 산 적 있어요?
Did he try selling you
that extended warranty?
그래.. 아마 있을꺼야
Yeah, he probably did.
멍청하게.. 그거에 낚여서,
산 게 있을꺼야
And I was probably
dumb enough to buy it.
예.. 그게 아빠의 최고 상술이었죠
Yeah, that was
his big thing.
한잔의 물을 요청하면
You ask him for
a glass of water,
보증기간 늘려준다면서,
얼음까지 팔아넘기실 분이죠
he'll tell you you need
an extended warranty on the ice.
- 그럼, 자네도 거기서 일했었나?
- 네
- So did you work there, too?
- Only my whole life,
뻑큐라고 소리치고, 그만두기 전 까진요
up until the day
I said "fuck you" and quit.
So, uh...
16년 전이면,
자넨 거기서 얼마나 있었던 거지?
16 years ago, how old
would you have been?
졸업하고 바로 거기 있었죠
It was after school.
Trust me, I was there.
아마, 아저씨도..
보증기간 늘려줄테니까
Might have even
helped ring you up.
애기침대 하나 장만하라는
내 전화 받아 봤을 걸요?
You and your extended
warranty on the crib.
세상 참 좁군
Small world.
그러게요
That it is.
그래,
우린 작은 오솔길에 있는거야
The paths we take, huh?
아저씨...
You...
저녀석도, 아저씨가 암인거 알아요?
Jesse know you got cancer?
아무도 몰라, 자네밖엔..
No one but you.
가족도요?
Not your family?
응
No.
왜요?
Why not?
말을 할 수 가 없더군..
Not a conversation I'm even
remotely ready to have.
그래서 마약을 만들게 된 건가요?
That's why
you're cooking meth?
가족에게,
돈이라도 남겨두고 가시게요?
You want to leave money
for your family.
날 풀어주면, ㅋ
수표라도 써 드리죠 ㅋ
Hell, I'll write you a check
right now if you let me go.
아까도 말했듯이,
Like I said, Walter,
이 일은, 아저씨랑 맞지 않아요
this line of work
doesn't suit you, man.
더 늦기 전에.. 빠져 나가세요
Get out
before it's too late.
나도 어찌해야 할 지, 모르겠네
I don't know what to do.
Yeah. You do.
열쇠 갖고 오겠네
I'll get the key.
안돼..
이럼 안돼
No, don't do this.
Don't do this.
자네, 왜 ..?
Why are you doing this?
자네, 왜 이런건가?
잘 생각 하신 거예요, 아저씨
You're doing
the right thing, Walter.
Do you want to...
그래.. 화나진 않은겐가?
So... you're not angry?
무슨 뜻 이죠?
How do you mean?
화를 요?
Angry?
아뇨
No.
풀어주세요
Live and let live, man.
내 말, 이해는 다 된건가?
That's very understanding.
네
Whatever, man.
집에 가고 싶어요
I just want to go home.
나도 마찬가지네..
Me, too.
풀어주세요, 아저씨
Unlock me, Walter.
풀어주는 순간,
The moment I do...
그 접시 조각으로 날 찌를건가?
are you gonna stick me
with that broken piece of plate?
미안하네,
미안해
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
미안하네
I'm sorry.
정말 미안하네...
I'm so sorry.
Hello?
밑에, 있어요?
Anybody down here?
얘들아!
Everybody!
제자리 못 앉어?
I need you all
to take your seats.
앉아, 얘들아!
그래..
Settle down, please.
Thank you.
화학 선생님이, 오늘 좀..
I understand
that Mr. White
사정이 있어서, 못 나오셨어
is feeling a little under
the weather this morning,
그래서 이번 시간은
so you folks
are going to have
선생님이랑 수업할 거야..
to be making do with me today.
이번 시간엔, 아주 아주 재밌는
And we are going
to be watching
비디오를 볼꺼야
a very interesting video on...
탄소
carbon.
아주 중요한 원소지
Very important stuff.
- 어떻게 생각하나?
- 이 자리에서, 마약 제조한 것 같아
- So what do you think?
- It's a cook site. Gotta be.
여긴 아무도 못 찾는 곳이잖아
Nobody came way the hell
out here just to buy.
불은 그냥 사고로 난 것 같아
Fire there could have
started by accident.
증거인멸을 위해, 낸 불은 아냐
Don't look like it was
meant to destroy evidence.
도로 쪽으로 찍혀있는,
바퀴자국으로 보아..
Got a couple of Dually tracks
headed away towards the road.
캠핑카 종류야
So, what, they're
in some kind of camper/lab.
사고로 불을 내고, 그냥 튄 건가?
They accidentally start a fire,
and everybody F.O.'s?
뻔한거 아냐?
Yeah, why not?
헤어젤을 왜 차에,
놔 두고 갔는지만 빼고는 말야
Except why would that little
hair-gelled shit leave his car?
이봐, 고미!
I-yi-yi, Gomie!
무선자동차 운전기판이잖아
It's a culture in decline.
진동이 요란하지
It's a rich and vibrant culture.
점프 업 N` 다운 하게 하지
It's a car that
jumps up and down.
What the hell?
주님의 은총으로 정복자가 돼었지
You people used to be conquistadors,
for Christ's sake.
이 차 안에서,
어둠의 냄새가 좀 나는데?
Smells like a Drakkar Noir
factory in here.
난, 이미 찾았네
I already searched it.
시간 낭비 말게나..
You're wasting your time.
포기하시지
Give it up.
우릴 낚기 위해 놓고 간 차라면,
If this here's a trap car,
약은, 뻔한 데 있는거 아니겠어?
it's gonna take more than
your dumb white ass to find it.
자넨, 이게 낚기위해 놓고간
차라고 보나?
You are talking to the trap car
master, my friend.
난, 이쑤시개까지 세는 레인맨일쎄
I'm Rain Man
counting his toothpicks.
그래, 자넨 레인맨이야
Yeah, you're like Rain Man.
저능아
Retarded.
자, 봐... 찾았지
Yeah, baby.
- 이거 봐, 지피..
- 족까
- Hello, Zippy.
- Asshole!
히로뽕 같은데..
근데, 좀.. 뭔가..
I'd say that looks
like meth, but it's...
너무 하얗지 않아?
it's too damn white.
내가 무슨 생각하고 있는지 알겠지?
You know what
I'm thinking, Gomie.
누군가, 용의자를 죽인거야
Somebody
croaked our snitch.
수사관님, 이거 좀 보세요
Hey, agents!
뭐 좀 있나?
You got something?
아.. 진짜 모르겠네
인체를 구성하는 요소 중에,
I don't know. Just...
우리가 분석 해내지 못한,
"0.111958%" 가 뭘까?
Doesn't it seem like...
뭐가 빠져있는지 알 수가 없어
something's missing?
영혼이 아닐까?
What about the soul?
영혼?
The soul.
과학만이 존재 할 뿐야
There's nothing
but chemistry here.
제작: [ 시 건 방 ]
dynas3@hanmail.net
college of Law in Korea Univ.
스카일러
Skyler.
당신과 할 얘기가 있어
There's something
I have to tell you.